That's Brother?
あれが兄者？
はい
Yes...
大神は我らと共にあったのです
Our God is with us.
How can this be?
こんなことが　全てはここにたどり着くために
決められていたことだっていうのか
All that has happened was for this.
Are you saying everything was predetermined?
No, we were led here.
いいえ 導かれたのです
うたわれるものに
By the one whose song is sung.
It was all because of you!
貴様がいるから
No, it's together that we bring misfortune.
いや 我らこそが災い
そうだ　我らこそが災い
That is correct. Together, we are misfortune.
It is we who are the leaders.
我らこそが元凶なるもの
It is we...
我らこそが
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空　果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に　充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼(はね)を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ　行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから　一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
Him Whose Song is Sung
What's the matter, you empty shell?
どうした 空蝉よ
This is not the extent of our power!
我らの力は そんなものではあるまい
That's better.
それでこそ
はあっ はあっ 抑えられぬ
I cannot suppress it.
Exactly. How can anything
suppress this urge?
そうだ　この衝動 どうして抑えられようか
At this moment, all that exists
for each of us is the other!
今この時 目の前に我が 汝が存在する
Since we are one and the same,
we abhor each other.
同じ存在であるからこそ 憎悪する
So, we have despised each other,
and led the people to this.
そうやって憎しみ合い 人を導いてきた
Now, what awaits beyond this point?
その先に何がある？
Peace.
安らぎ
はっ　安らぎ？
Peace!?
When my children achieve my ideal,
I will be released from eternal solitude.
我が子らが 我の高みにたどり着いた時
無限の孤独から解放される
それこそが願い
That is exactly what my goal is.
That is all you have done this for?
そんなことのために
これでも まだ思い出せぬか
You still don't remember!?
フフフ　よく眠っているな
She is sleeping so peacefully.
That's all she does.
寝てばかりです
Just another way in which
she takes after you.
そういうところも 君にそっくりだ
I'm not always sleeping.
私は寝てばかりじゃないです
アッハハハ　あ そうだ
Oh, right! Here...
これを
What is this?
これって…
It is something precious that
your father gave us.
お前のお父さんがくれた 大切な物だよ
わあ
May this child have nothing but happiness.
この子に幸多からんことを
Run! Mikoto!
逃げろ ミコト　うわあっ
No!
いやあー！
-ううっ ああっ あっ…
-返して 私の赤ちゃん
Give me back my baby!
返してー！
Mikoto...
ミコ… ト
あーん　あーん
You've come to, Iceman?
お目覚めかね アイスマン
くっ 貴様あ
Why, you...
Look at this. It is a replica of your mask.
見てくれたまえ　君の仮面のレプリカだ
Ah, wonderful!
ああ 素晴らしい　素晴らしいよ
It's wonderful!
これを着けているだけで 力が湧き上がる
I put this on and I can feel my power build.
My metabolism and immunity are
greater than ever before.
代謝能力も免疫力も
これまでの比ではない
With this, it won't be long before we humans will be
able to return to the surface of the Earth.
これで我々人類が
再び地上へ帰る日も遠くない
Mikoto...
ミコト
うん？　ミコト？
Mikoto?
Oh, the test subject?
ああ あの実験体かね
She is a valuable sample, having
been the first to bear a child.
初めて母体となった貴重なサンプルだ
解体して大切にしてある
I had her dissected and carefully preserved.
Dissected?
解体？
There's nothing to be concerned about.
何 気にすることはない
あんなのが好みなら 同じものを10体でも
20体でも 好きなだけ作ってやろうじゃないか
If she was to your liking, I can make ten,
twenty or as many more of her as you like!
Is that...
そんなに…
Is that how much you desire
a more powerful body?
そんなに強い肉体が欲しいか
Is that how much you desire
a body that won't die?
そんなに死なない体が欲しいか
Then I shall grant your wish!
ならばその望み かなえてやろう
わああー
あ… 何だ これは　わああー
What's happening?
I shall give you a body that will live forever.
未来永劫生き続ける
不死の体にしてやろう
I will give you eternal life.
Help me!
助けてくれー
ううっ あっ うわあー きゃあー
Stop it... Stop it.
やめろ やめろ　誰が止めてくれ　止めてくれ
Somebody stop me!
Stop me... Please stop me...
私を止めてくれ それが
かなわぬのなら 我を滅せよ！
If you can't do that...
then destroy me!
All right...
いいよ
Father, you've finally returned to me.
お父様 やっと帰って来てくれた
Father?
お父様？
Your wish is my wish, Father.
お父様の望みは 私の望みだから
Farewell...
さよなら
However, not even Mutsumi
was able to destroy me.
だが ムツミにも
我を滅することはできなかった
Having no choice, Mutsumi
sealed me in this land.
やむなくムツミは 我をこの地に封じた
But my spirit had split in two
before I was sealed,
そして 封じられる前に分かれた２つの心は
戻ることなく 我らはそのまま眠りについた
and I fell into a deep sleep without
reuniting with my other half.
そう
Yes!
And when we awakened on the Earth,
we interfered with our children!
そして 我らは目覚めては地にい出て
我が子らに干渉してきた
So that we could lead our children
to a higher level!
我が子らを高みに導くためだ
That pride has caused them all great suffering!
その傲りが 人を苦しめている
Hakuoro-san!
ハクオロさん
I shall lead the people!
我は人を導く
No! We are unnecessary.
否　我らは無用　人は己の意思で生きていく
People will live of their own free wills.
What!?
何？
再び１つになるというのか
Are you trying to make us one again?
Let us go now...
行こう　我が分身よ
my other half!
Hakuoro-san...
ハクオロさん
Eruruu, I am as you see me.
エルルゥ 見てのとおりだ　自分は…
I've known about that for a long time.
そんなの ずっと前から気付いてました
ハクオロさんはハクオロさんです
But you are still Hakuoro-san to me!
You still call me by that name?
自分をまだ その名で呼んでくれるのか
Father, you can't go!
お父さん 行っちゃ駄目
残念だが 自分は
I am sorry, but I...
ちゃんと言うこと聞く　だから だから
I will do as you say, so... so...
With the way I am now, I won't be
patting your head anymore.
この姿では もうお前を
なでてやることができないな
No!
嫌
は… 分かってくれ
Please understand...
You're a liar! A liar, liar, liar...
嘘つき　嘘つき 嘘つき 嘘つき
You said we'd always be together!
ずっと一緒って言った　ずっと
お父さん ずっと一緒じゃないと嫌
I don't ever want to be away
from you, Father!
Brother...
兄者
Urutori...
ウルトリィ
Yes?
はい
You must seal me.
我を封印するんだ
Why do you hesitate?
何をためらっている
But...
ですが…
やるんだ
Do it!
For a human to seal Witsalnemitea...
人の手でウィツァルネミテアを
封じるなんて
その罪
That sin...
is one I will bear with you.
一緒に背負ってあげる
- Camus-cchi!
- Aruruu!
カミュちー
アルルゥ
If you choose to sleep, Father,
お父様が眠りを選ぶと言うのなら
私も従うだけ
I can only obey your wish.
And so, I'll return this child.
だから この子を返すね
はっ カミュ
Camus!
I'm finally home, Big Sister.
お姉様 ただいま
Camus...
カミュ
Big Sister!
お姉様
This is as it should be.
I am a being that should not exist.
これでいい　私はあってはならない存在
Hakuoro-san!
ハクオロさん
Do it, Urutori, before my
other self breaks out!
やるんだ ウルトリィ
もう１人の私が暴れ出す前に
I shall begin.
行きます
We, of the Onkamiyamukai...
我らはオンカミヤリュー
We, who have borne this
destiny since antiquity...
我らは大罪を背負い
宿命付けられた者なり
This is good.
これでいい
We now open the prison gates once again,
今ここに再び牢獄の門を開け
我らが父をコトゥアハムルへいざなわん
and send our Father to the Beyond.
Do it!
やるんだ
くっ… おうっ
Brother!
兄者ー！
うぬっ
えいっ
Father...
お父さん
Urutori...
ウルトリィ
Yes?
はい
There will probably be more
fighting in the future.
この先も まだ争いが続くだろう
When that happens, I want you to be the bridge
その時 お前が懸け橋となって
仲を取り持ってやってほしい
and mediate between the parties.
Yes, I will do as you bid.
はい　確かに承りました
Mister!
おじ様
Camus... Or are you Mutsumi?
カミュ それともムツミか
I am Camus now.
今はカミュだよ
I caused you much suffering.
お前を苦しめてしまったな
No, it's all right.
ううん 大丈夫　ムツミもきっと 喜んでる
I'm sure Mutsumi is happy too.
I see.
そうか
Mister, please don't forget about me.
おじ様 カミュのこと 忘れないでね
No, I will not forget ever again.
ああ　今度は決して忘れない
Not such a feisty, sweet girl, who always
needs the company of others.
おてんばで寂しがりな 可愛い娘を
Mister...
おじ様
Karula...
カルラ
Yes?
はい
You are not one to be tied down.
本来お前は 何かに縛られる質ではない
From now on, live freely.
これからは好きに生きるといい
Oh, dear, you don't need to tell me that!
I've always lived my life as I wanted.
あら 言われるまでもなく
好き勝手に生きてましたわ
Yes, I guess so.
そうだったな
そして これからも
And from here on, I will still
belong to you, my Master.
私が主様のものであることには
変わりありませんわ
某も どこまでもお供したく思いまする
As will I! I wish to accompany
you wherever you go.
Touka, you have served me well.
You have my gratitude.
トウカ よく尽くしてくれた
礼を言う
I do not deserve such words.
もったいなきお言葉
これからも戦乱は絶えぬだろう
The fighting will probably go on endlessly,
そして その犠牲になるのは
力を持たぬ弱き者たち
and the victims will be the
powerless and weak.
Please help those people, like Genjimaru did.
その者たちの力になってくれ
あのゲンジマルのように
Yes, sire! On my life!
はっ　この命に代えましても
Benawi...
ベナウィ
Yes, sire.
クロウ
Kurou...
ういっす
Yessir.
I appreciate all your help.
お前たちにも世話になった
Please leave the rest to us,
and have a good rest.
後は我々に任せ どうかごゆるりと
Right, take care of everyone.
ああ　皆のことを頼む
I was able to use this life that
you saved in service to you.
あの時 聖上に救われた命
こうしてお仕えできたこと
It has been deeply rewarding
to me, as a warrior.
武士（もののふ）として
実に本懐でありました
Commander, let's not be so formal.
総大将 堅苦しいのは無しですぜ
You are right, Kurou.
Please continue to support everyone.
そうだな クロウ
これからも皆を支えてやってくれ
Yessir! I hear you loud and clear.
ういっす
総大将のお言葉 しかと承りやしたぜ
Oboro, I entrust you with the power
to lead everyone from here on.
オボロ
後のことはお前に委ねる
これからは お前が皆を導くんだ
ぐっ　そんなことどうだっていい
I don't care about that!
I swore I would always be
by your side, didn't I?
俺は 兄者と共にあることを誓ったはずだ
We did too, honorable Brother!
兄者様 僕たちも
We did!
僕たちも
Dori, Gura...
ドリィ グラァ
You look after Oboro.
オボロを頼むぞ
Yes, sire!
はい
Oboro, you cannot leave Yuzuha behind, can you?
オボロ ユズハを置いては行けないだろう
Please understand.
分かってくれ
う… 分かった
All right, leave the rest to me then.
後のことは任せてくれ
No! I'll go with you.
やだー アルルゥも一緒に行く
What will happen to Eruruu
if you are gone too, Aruruu?
アルルゥまでいなくなってしまったら
エルルゥはどうなる
What will happen to everyone
you leave behind?
残された者はどうなる
アルルゥにはエルルゥがいる
You have Eruruu...
You have friends...
友達がいる　たくさんの兄や 姉がいる
and lots of big brothers and sisters.
But...
でも… うっ お父さんいない
You'll be gone...
うっ お父さんいない…
You'll be gone!
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
Hakuoro-san...
ハクオロさん
kimi no hitomi ni utsuru
Reflecting in your eyes...
So, you're leaving then, Hakuoro-san.
ハクオロさん
行っちゃうんですね
ああ　しばらくの間 眠らせてもらう
Yes, please allow me to sleep for a while.
watashi wa nani iro desu ka
What color am I?
Please leave the rest to us.
後のことは 任せてください
You don't have to worry about a thing.
ハクオロさんは 何の心配もしなくて
大丈夫なんですよ
aka fukaki nozomu nara
If you yearn for red,
I know.
watasou hi no hikari wo
let me give you the light of day.
You said "a while. " How long is a while?
しばらくって… しばらくって
どのくらいですか
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
家族だって言ったじゃないですか
You said we were family, didn't you?
You asked us to stay with you, didn't you?
一緒にいてくれって
言ったじゃないですか
No, please don't go.
嫌 行かないで
Eruruu, your feelings are not real.
エルルゥ
お前のその気持ちは
契約で刻まれたまやかし
They are the result of your pact.
That's not true!
違います
私 ハクオロさんが人じゃないことも
I knew that you weren't human,
and that you were suffering because of that.
kanashimi ga afure
Sadness overflowed
そのことで苦しんでいたことも
みんな知ってました
But it doesn't matter.
でも そんなの関係ないです
mabuta tojimashita
and I closed my eyes.
You saved Aruruu.
ハクオロさんは
アルルゥを助けてくれました
私たちにぬくもりをくれました
You gave us your warmth.
koboreta shizuku wa kokoro ni shimiyuku
The spilling water drops seep into my heart.
You worked so hard, saying it was for
the sake of everyone else.
皆のためにって 一生懸命で
That's the Hakuoro I love!
そんなハクオロさんが好きでした
I wanted to tell you that I loved you.
好きですって言いたかった
ハクオロさんが傷付いて 苦しんで
悩んでいた時 抱きしめてあげたかった
When you were in pain because of your injuries,
yukiwataru nami wa yowaku majiemasu
The waves softly mix together.
I wanted to hold you in my arms.
The pact has nothing to do with it!
契約なんて関係ないです
これからは抱きしめてあげられます
I would continue to hold you too!
But...
なのに
Thank you...
ありがとう
todokeshi yurikago nemuri wo sasou
The delivered cradle invites sleep.
Your words are so unfair.
そんな言い方って ずるいです
They are so unfair!
ずるいですよ
Mikoto...
ミコト？
ふっ 今頃気付くとはな
To think I never realized it until now...
yume ni natsukashii omokage wo sagasu
I look for a nostalgic vestige in my dreams.
あっ ハクオロさん
Hakuoro-san!
来るな！
Stay there!
You must not come.
来ては 駄目だ
te wo nobashi tsuyoku dakishimetaku naru
Extending my arms, I want to hold you tight.
I am sure there will come a day
when we will meet again.
きっと また会える時が来る
kimi no hitomi ni utsuru
Reflecting in your eyes...
I am sure...
きっと
watashi wa nani iro desu ka
What color am I?
ai fukaki nozomu nara
If you yearn for blue,
Here, the bell you loved so much.
ほら お前が好きだった鈴だ
watasou takaki sora wo
let me give you these far-reaching skies.
Well, I'll be going, Yuzuha.
それじゃあ行ってくるよ ユズハ
Are you really going?
本当に行くのですか
Yeah, I'll leave things in your
hands for a while.
ああ　しばらくの間 頼んだぞ
I'm still green.
俺はまだ未熟だ　玉座に座る器じゃない
yorokobi ga afure
The happiness overflowed
I am not ready to take the throne.
Brother...
兄者
meguriaimashita
and we found each other.
My lord!
若様ー
うっ 僕たちも一緒に
We will go with you.
No, I think it's time you two were released
from the pledge made by your parents.
いや お前たちも もう親の代からの
盟約などに縛られることもないだろう
kaboreotsu emi wa wakare wo kakusu
Our overflowing smiles hid our farewell.
You have done your jobs well.
From now on, you...
これまでよく仕えてくれた　これからは…
No!
嫌です
For us to not to be able to serve you...
もう若様にお仕えできないなんて
イネボクシに落ちた方がましです
We would rather suffer the
hellfire of Dinebokushiri!
hito wa itsushika kuchihateru keredo
Before you know it, people will rot away...
Please, take us with you!
お願いします どうか一緒に
ふっ 勝手にしろ
Then do as you wish.
Right! We shall follow you!
はい
勝手にします
kouta to nari
becoming but a ballad...
katari tsugarete yuku desho
which will continue to be passed down for generations.
貴様は退屈だからといって
仲間をアンクァムとして売り飛ばすのか
You're telling me you sold your own comrade as
a mercenary just because you were bored?
I haven't sold you.
売り飛ばしてなんかいませんわよ
Why, I haven't received any money at all!
お金なんてもらってませんもの　んぐっ
kimi no hitomi ni utsuru
Reflecting in your eyes...
Then, how did you get that sake?
では その酒はどこで手に入れた？
Bartered for it.
交換しましたの
世間ではそれを売ったと言うんだ
In this world, that is the same as selling!
watashi wa nani iro desu ka
What color am I?
Oh, sire, we still have so much to learn.
ああ聖上 某はまだまだ
未熟でございますう
ryoku fukaki nozomu nara
If you yearn for green,
ほらほら 走らないとやられますわよ
Come on, you'd better keep running
or they'll get you.
むう　いいっ？
watasou kono daichi wo
let me give you these lands.
High Priest!
オルヤンクルー
ううっ また姫様が
こんなものを残してどこかへ
The princess left this and disappeared again.
しょうのない子　フフフ
She's incorrigible!
This is no laughing matter!
笑い事ではございませんぞ
It's all right.
良いのですよ　あの子は今
大切なことを学んでいるのですから
She is learning something
very important right now.
kimi no hitomi ni utsuru
Reflecting in your eyes...
Oh...
watashi wa nani iro desu ka
What color am I?
Kuuya-sama, it is time for your nap.
クーヤ様　そろそろお昼寝の時間ですよ
yasuragi oboeta nara
If you have learned of tranquility,
What is it?
どうしたんですか
soko ni watashi wa iru
I am there.
kimi no hitomi ni utsuru
Reflecting in your eyes...
Thank you!
ありがとう　あむ　うーん おいしいね
It's delicious, isn't it?
watashi wa nani iro desu ka
What color am I?
But are you all right?
It looks like you got stung pretty bad.
でも 大丈夫？
結構刺されちゃったみたいだけど
うーん　蜂の巣取る 難しい
ura fukaki nozomu nara
If you yearn for the opposite,
It's hard taking a beehive.
But the harder it is, the yummier it tastes.
難しいほど おいしい
watasou kono omoi wo
I'll give you these feelings.
Well, if you say so.
アルちゃんがそう言うなら
watasou kono subete wo
I'll give you this everything.
Huh? What's the matter?
グゥ…
どうしたの
Hello, Granny.
こんにちは おばあちゃん
Hello, Eruruu-sama.
エルルゥ様 こんにちは
足の調子はどうですか
How is your leg?
はい おかげさまで
Much better, thanks to you.
Now I can fight with my devil
of a daughter-in-law again.
これでまた 鬼嫁と戦えますわい
ヒッヒヒヒ
ウフフフ　ほどほどにね
Well, don't overdo it.
エルルゥお姉ちゃん
Eruruu-oneechan!
Oh, my, should you be up
and around so soon?
あら もう起きて大丈夫なの？
Yeah, I'm even helping my ma already.
うん　もう母ちゃんの
手伝いだってしてるんだ
I see, that's wonderful.
そう　偉いんだね
エルルゥ様 このたびは
何とお礼を言ったらよいやら
Eruruu-sama, I don't know how to thank you.
Why, all I did was help a little.
いいえ　私はちょっと手助けしただけで
この子は 自分の力で治ったんです
This child healed all by himself.
Eruruu-sama, we've got trouble!
エルルゥ様 大変だー えふっ ふうっ
またじいさんの腰が抜けちまった
Gramps threw his back again.
Oh, my, again?
まあ　また？
早く 早く
Hurry! Hurry!
Hakuoro-san, I am here.
ハクオロさん 私はここにいます
I am here with Aruruu.
アルルゥと一緒に ここにいます
I will be here forever and ever,
waiting for you...
ずっとずっと ここであなたを